<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Archives | News | Monmouth University</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/archives/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.monmouth.edu/news</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 22:13:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Nursing Students Administer COVID-19 Vaccines</title>
		<link>https://www.monmouth.edu/news/nursing-students-administer-covid-19-vaccines/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Glatz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 19:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Campus and Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experiential Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giving Back]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monmouth Now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Covid-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Outlook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Monmouth University nursing students administered COVID-19 vaccines at Brookdale Community College as a part of their clinical experiences, their third time administering vaccines in total, on Tuesday, March 23.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/nursing-students-administer-covid-19-vaccines/">Nursing Students Administer COVID-19 Vaccines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Monmouth University nursing students administered COVID-19 vaccines at Brookdale Community College as a part of their clinical experiences, their third time administering vaccines in total, on Tuesday, March 23.</p>



<p>The students have previously worked with RWJ Barnabas Health, Monmouth Medical Center, and the Monmouth County Health Department to administer vaccines at various New Jersey locations. Currently, the School of Nursing is working with the Visiting Nursing Association of Central Jersey (VNACJ) to have students participate at the organization’s vaccination sites.</p>



<p>Laura Jannone, Ed.D., associate professor and coordinator of the Nursing program, arranged the participation of the pre-licensure baccalaureate nursing students in local COVID-19 vaccine clinics, at the direction of Dean of the School of Nursing and Health Studies Ann Marie Mauro, Ph.D.</p>



<p>“[Our students] are part of history,” Jannone said. “Nursing during a pandemic is extremely important—not only in caring for the sick, but also in preventing illness by participating in vaccine clinics. They get to witness how the response team sets up and rolls out the mass point of distribution (POD) clinic… Students have the opportunity to provide essential health care during a pandemic and to protect the public from COVID-19 through mass vaccination efforts.”</p>



<p>Rachel Blackwell, a sophomore nursing student, described treating the 1200 people who arrived at the clinic for either their first or second dose as a very rewarding experience. “This vaccination clinic helped me practice skills that I will continue to use here and in my nursing career,” Blackwell said, noting that Monmouth’s nursing labs have helped prepare her for the experience.</p>



<p>Heather Orgonas, also a sophomore nursing student, agreed that the experience was very beneficial to her educational journey. “Being a part of this vaccine clinic allowed me and my fellow nursing students the opportunity to put some of the skills we learned in the lab into actual practice. This definitely helped us to further strengthen our education and our job-related performance,” she said.</p>



<p>If getting the vaccine is scary for some, administering the vaccine is at a whole other level, but the nursing students proved up to the challenge.</p>



<p>“At the beginning of the day, I was pretty nervous to be giving out the vaccines as I did not want to hurt anyone or possibly perform the skill incorrectly. But once the day went on, and I had given out a few rounds of injections, I definitely calmed down and was really able to focus on the goal of the day,” Orgonas said.</p>



<p>“We met and spoke to a lot of great people that day, and it overall felt really rewarding to be able to help out in distributing these vaccinations in the fight against COVID-19,” she said.</p>



<p>Blackwell agreed, “I was anxious to administer my first dose, [but] after I gave the first injection, I gained more confidence and felt more relaxed. I felt proud being able to give an individual a vaccine that can keep them from getting seriously ill and ending up in a hospital.”</p>



<p> “I am very proud of the Monmouth Pre-Licensure BSN students. They arrive at 7:15 a.m. and work a full day giving vaccines, going over health questionnaires, and observing for side effects. The students are compassionate and empathetic. They listen to the stories of the people getting vaccines, some of whom have lost loved ones to COVID-19,” Jannone said.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>A version of <a href="https://outlook.monmouth.edu/features/179-volume-93-fall-2020-spring-2021/7665-nursing-students-administer-covid-19-vaccines">this story</a> was originally published in the Volume 93 (Fall 2020 &#8211; Spring 2021) edition of The Outlook by Denisse Quintanilla, junior Spanish and Communication student with a concentration in media studies and production.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/nursing-students-administer-covid-19-vaccines/">Nursing Students Administer COVID-19 Vaccines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/04/IMG_7824-3.2.jpg" length="66897" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monmouth University Promotes Jeff Stapleton to Athletic Director</title>
		<link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/colleges/monmouth-u-promotes-jeff-stapleton-to-athletic-director/2021/04/05/efff05a0-9637-11eb-8f0a-3384cf4fb399_story.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 12:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Awards, Honors, and Appointments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Campus and Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monmouth In The News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Monmouth University is promoting deputy athletic director Jeff Stapleton to replace Marilyn McNeil as head of the department. University president Patrick Leahy announced the promotion on Monday, saying it would be effective in July.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/colleges/monmouth-u-promotes-jeff-stapleton-to-athletic-director/2021/04/05/efff05a0-9637-11eb-8f0a-3384cf4fb399_story.html">Monmouth University Promotes Jeff Stapleton to Athletic Director</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/colleges/monmouth-u-promotes-jeff-stapleton-to-athletic-director/2021/04/05/efff05a0-9637-11eb-8f0a-3384cf4fb399_story.html">Monmouth University Promotes Jeff Stapleton to Athletic Director</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/04/Jeff_Stapleton-1024x576.jpg" length="100811" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Panel: &#8220;Genetics, Genomics, and Racism&#8221; April 8</title>
		<link>https://www.monmouth.edu/news/panel-genetics-genomics-and-racism-april-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 18:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Campus and Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity and Inclusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intercultural Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspectives, Publications, and Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Megan Phifer-Rixey, Ph.D., assistant professor in the Department of Biology, and Jennifer McGovern, Ph.D., assistant professor in the Department of Political Science and Sociology, are the organizers of an online panel discussion, “Genetics, Genomics, &#38; Racism: How Science Shapes Policy Past, Present, Future,” on April 8 at 7:30 p.m. The event is free, but registration [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/panel-genetics-genomics-and-racism-april-8/">Panel: &#8220;Genetics, Genomics, and Racism&#8221; April 8</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Megan Phifer-Rixey, Ph.D., assistant professor in the Department of Biology, and Jennifer McGovern, Ph.D., assistant professor in the Department of Political Science and Sociology, are the organizers of an online panel discussion, “Genetics, Genomics, &amp; Racism: How Science Shapes Policy Past, Present, Future,” on April 8 at 7:30 p.m. <a href="https://monmouth.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJwtd-GrqT0uH9AE84tSvERNcckJUH8wiMOT">The event is free, but registration is required</a>.</p>
<p>Kiameesha Evans, MPH, MCHES, specialist professor in the Department of Health and Physical Education, will moderate the discussion, which will examine the complicated relationship between genetics, genomics, and racism. Featured speakers Krystal Tsosie and Gabriela Corona Valencia will discuss their research as doctoral candidates and consider both the legacy of past genetic technologies and the future impacts of new genomic initiatives.</p>
<p>Krystal Tsosie<strong>,</strong> MPH, M.A., a doctoral candidate at Vanderbilt University, is already a leader in her field. Her voice has been critical in shaping policy on genomics initiatives in indigenous communities, particularly with respect to the ethics of consent and data sovereignty. Her research integrates both efforts to improve health outcomes for indigenous communities through genomics and efforts to address the ethics of obtaining and using genomic data.</p>
<p>Gabriela Corona Valencia, M.A., is a doctoral candidate at the Graduate School of Education and Information Studies at UCLA. Her dissertation research highlights the ways in which eugenicist ideologies continue to influence sex education curricula and initiatives that are implemented across South and East Los Angeles.</p>
<p>The program is sponsored by Monmouth University’s Diversity Innovation Grant program, which is supported by the Office of the Provost and the Intercultural Center with support from the School of Science and the School of Humanities and Social Sciences. The event is also possible thanks to support from student coordinator Cameron Gaines and the students of BY216-H1 (Introduction to Genetics) and SO101-H1 (Introduction to Sociology).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/panel-genetics-genomics-and-racism-april-8/">Panel: &#8220;Genetics, Genomics, and Racism&#8221; April 8</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/04/21-Genetics_Genomics_Racism_Event-03-1.jpg" length="105870" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Professor Estes Presents &#8220;Weather in Old English Literature&#8221; April 10</title>
		<link>https://www.monmouth.edu/news/professor-estes-presents-weather-in-old-english-literature-april-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 18:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Faculty Accomplishments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspectives, Publications, and Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Heide Estes, Ph.D., professor of English, will present &#8220;Weather in Old English Literature&#8221; as a virtual presentation on April 10 at 11 a.m. as part of the bi-annual works-in-progress seminar, “Ecocriticism &#38; Premodern Studies,” presented by the Medieval and Renaissance Studies program at the University of Missouri. Estes is the author of “Anglo-Saxon Literary Landscapes: [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/professor-estes-presents-weather-in-old-english-literature-april-10/">Professor Estes Presents &#8220;Weather in Old English Literature&#8221; April 10</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heide Estes, Ph.D., professor of English, will present &#8220;Weather in Old English Literature&#8221; as a virtual presentation on April 10 at 11 a.m. as part of the bi-annual works-in-progress seminar, “Ecocriticism &amp; Premodern Studies,” presented by the Medieval and Renaissance Studies program at the University of Missouri.</p>
<p>Estes is the author of “<a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt1zkjxx3">Anglo-Saxon Literary Landscapes: Ecotheory and the Environmental Imagination</a>,” and was recently elected a member of the executive committee for the Old English Language and Literature Committee of the Modern Language Association.</p>
<p>For free registration, papers, and Zoom link, please email Professor Megan Moore at <a href="mailto:mooremegan@missouri.edu">mooremegan@missouri.edu</a>.</p>
<h2 class="page-title"></h2>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/professor-estes-presents-weather-in-old-english-literature-april-10/">Professor Estes Presents &#8220;Weather in Old English Literature&#8221; April 10</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/04/Heide-Estes-Headshot_20190925_AD_03-1024x683.jpg" length="689319" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Abate Will Moderate &#8220;An Undertaking Overseas: Global Protection of Coastal and Marine Wildlife&#8221; April 9</title>
		<link>https://www.monmouth.edu/news/abate-will-moderate-an-undertaking-overseas-global-protection-of-coastal-and-marine-wildlife-april-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 18:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academic Excellence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Institute for Global Understanding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspectives, Publications, and Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Coast Institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IGU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UCI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The field of animal law has grown rapidly and extensively in recent decades. Examples of animal law in practice that immediately come to mind may be limited: the enactment of anti-cruelty statutes, or the protection of endangered species. But animal law cannot be neatly delineated as its own legal niche. Animal rights advocates have propelled the boundaries of animal law to intersect with most traditional fields of the law: constitutional, criminal, tort, environmental, business, family, consumer protection, entertainment.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/abate-will-moderate-an-undertaking-overseas-global-protection-of-coastal-and-marine-wildlife-april-9/">Abate Will Moderate &#8220;An Undertaking Overseas: Global Protection of Coastal and Marine Wildlife&#8221; April 9</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Randall Abate, professor in the Department of Political Science and Sociology, Rechnitz Family/Urban Coast Institute Endowed Chair in Marine and Environmental Law and Policy, and director of the Institute for Global Understanding, will serve as moderator for a panel discussion, &#8220;An Undertaking Overseas: Global Protection of Coastal and Marine Wildlife,&#8221; on April 9 at 11:45 a.m.</p>
<p>The discussion is part of an online two-day symposium, &#8220;<a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/a-wild-approach-creating-a-global-lens-for-animal-welfare-registration-146822581293">A Wild Approach: Creating a Global Lens for Animal Welfare through International Law and Policy</a>,&#8221; sponsored by the Connecticut Journal of International Law to explore strategies for protecting animal welfare through international law and policy.</p>
<p>Panelists include Francine Kershaw, staff scientist at the Natural Resources Defense Council; Jaclyn Lopez, senior attorney at the Center for Biological Diversity; and Amy Wilson, legal fellow, Aquatic Animal Law Initiative at Lewis &amp; Clark Law School.</p>
<p>The event will provide a critical look at how we serve the particular needs of coastal and marine wildlife through international and domestic law and policy. Panelists will discuss the efficacy of legislative initiatives such as the Marine Mammal Protection Act, the Endangered Species Act, and the National Environmental Policy Act.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/a-wild-approach-creating-a-global-lens-for-animal-welfare-registration-146822581293">This event is free for students and the general public, but registration is required</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/abate-will-moderate-an-undertaking-overseas-global-protection-of-coastal-and-marine-wildlife-april-9/">Abate Will Moderate &#8220;An Undertaking Overseas: Global Protection of Coastal and Marine Wildlife&#8221; April 9</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/04/Crop_129403497_202204477195_1_original.jpg" length="17323" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Fletcher Lake Water Quality Sampling Instruction</title>
		<link>https://www.monmouth.edu/uci/2021/03/31/fletcher-lake/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 12:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Campus and Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giving Back]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Great Location]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Coast Institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UCI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Urban Coast Institute Citizen Science Coordinator Erin Conlon and Endowed Associate Professor in Marine Science Jason Adolf recently trained local high school students to conduct water quality sampling at Fletcher Lake in Bradley Beach. The effort was part of the Coastal Lakes Observing Network (CLONet) project, which is focused on monitoring the health of seaside lakes in Monmouth County.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/uci/2021/03/31/fletcher-lake/">WATCH: Fletcher Lake Water Quality Sampling Instruction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/uci/2021/03/31/fletcher-lake/">WATCH: Fletcher Lake Water Quality Sampling Instruction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/04/DSC04903-1024x683.jpg" length="866457" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Gamers are Re-creating All of N.J. in Minecraft, Down to Every Pothole and Jug-handle&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://www.nj.com/entertainment/2021/04/gamers-are-re-creating-all-of-nj-in-minecraft-down-to-every-pothole-and-jug-handle.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 14:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Great Location]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monmouth In The News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“New Jersey feels very unique in terms of architecture and road layout. It’s pretty cool to see that represented in a video game... you can (build), for example, Route 22 and a jug-handle and you’ll immediately know that nowhere else has roads that look like that even though it’s a game made out of blocks,” said Brodowski, a student a Monmouth University.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nj.com/entertainment/2021/04/gamers-are-re-creating-all-of-nj-in-minecraft-down-to-every-pothole-and-jug-handle.html">&#8220;Gamers are Re-creating All of N.J. in Minecraft, Down to Every Pothole and Jug-handle&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nj.com/entertainment/2021/04/gamers-are-re-creating-all-of-nj-in-minecraft-down-to-every-pothole-and-jug-handle.html">&#8220;Gamers are Re-creating All of N.J. in Minecraft, Down to Every Pothole and Jug-handle&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/04/7DSGSRZJX5H5LGBNP5JKV44S4E-1024x578.jpg" length="97175" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Students and Faculty Present at Eastern Psychological Association Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.monmouth.edu/news/students-and-faculty-present-at-eastern-psychological-association-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Glatz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 17:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Monmouth Now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspectives, Publications, and Research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Students and faculty of the Department of Psychology virtually attended and presented at the Eastern Psychological Association (EPA) conference held on March 5 and 6, 2021. This year’s presentations from Monmouth faculty and students included: “The Connection Between Emotional Intelligence and Social Justice,” presented by Professor Natalie Ciarocco and Natalie Delgado; “The Effect on Diversity [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/students-and-faculty-present-at-eastern-psychological-association-conference/">Students and Faculty Present at Eastern Psychological Association Conference</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Students and faculty of the Department of Psychology virtually attended and presented at the Eastern Psychological Association (EPA) conference held on March 5 and 6, 2021.</p>



<p>This year’s presentations from Monmouth faculty and students included: “The Connection Between Emotional Intelligence and Social Justice,” presented by Professor Natalie Ciarocco and Natalie Delgado; “The Effect on Diversity on Self-Efficacy in Private University,” presented by Associate Professor Janice Stapley and Samuel Aydukovic; and “The Effect of Professors Ethnicity on Students’ Evaluations,” presented by Stapley, Ciarocco, and Senior Lecturer Michele Van Volkom.</p>



<p>Lindsay Mehrkam, Ph.D., adviser of the Psychology Club, presented with psychology majors Sarah Cooper and Nicholas Quinn; Cooper presented on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HlCT1RJy_pI">&#8220;Public Perceptions of Mental Health Assistance Animals,&#8221;</a> while Quinn&#8217;s research focused on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FPzR7byJTSM">&#8220;The Effects of Social Interactions on Psychological Well-Being of Dogs and Owners.&#8221;</a> Mehrkam also presented with recent Monmouth University alumni Sojourney Gray ’20, Laura Swinyer ’20, and Tyra Ward ’19.</p>



<p>Additionally, Mehrkam participated in a learning symposium, “What Fish Can Teach Undergraduates About Learning, Behavior, and Research,” alongside comparative psychologists Ruth Colwill (Brown University) and Peter Basalm (Columbia University). In her talk, Mehrkam highlighted how students in Monmouth’s ‘Psychology of Learning’ course study basic learning concepts and principles, in part by having students teach goldfish new behaviors using positive reinforcement training, enrichment, and welfare assessments.</p>



<p>Kaitlyn Hogan, vice president of Psychology Club, reflected on the annual trip, “I always look forward to each year’s EPA conference because I enjoy learning about new studies and the statistically significant results discovered.”</p>



<p>Angelina D’Acunto, social media coordinator of Psychology Club, added, “One important message that stuck out was the importance of equity. As a woman scientist, it is important for me to see other women and minority groups represented in the field of psychology.”</p>



<p>Natalie Delgado, president of the Monmouth University Psi Chi Chapters, said, “Attending EPA was one of the most rewarding and eye-opening experiences in my academic career thus far. It has been a dream of mine to give a presentation at a regional conference ever since my interest in research began sophomore year.”</p>



<p>In past years, over 25 students annually attend the weekend conference which rotates locations in New York, Philadelphia, or Boston. Students’ travel expenses are covered through the generous support of the Department of Psychology, Psychology Club, and the Psi Chi Honor Society.</p>



<p>The EPA was founded in 1896 and is the oldest of the regional Psychological Associations in the United States. Its sole purpose is to advance the science and profession through the dissemination of professional information about the field of psychology, and provide an opportunity for scholars, practitioners, and students of psychology to convene annually to share research and ideas that foster the development of the discipline.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-40802254316" src="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-1120x840.jpg 1120w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-560x420.jpg 560w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-280x210.jpg 280w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-320x240.jpg 320w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-2800x2100.jpg 2800w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-1400x1050.jpg 1400w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-360x270.jpg 360w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-2667x2000.jpg 2667w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1-150x113.jpg 150w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA-2021-Poster-Quinn-Mehrkam-1.jpg 4800w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /> <img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-40802254318" src="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-1120x840.jpg 1120w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-560x420.jpg 560w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-280x210.jpg 280w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-320x240.jpg 320w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-2800x2100.jpg 2800w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-1400x1050.jpg 1400w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-360x270.jpg 360w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-2667x2000.jpg 2667w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1-150x113.jpg 150w, https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/EPA_2021_Stapley_Ciarocco_VanVolkom-1.jpg 4800w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/students-and-faculty-present-at-eastern-psychological-association-conference/">Students and Faculty Present at Eastern Psychological Association Conference</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/Sarah-Cooper.jpg" length="59818" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Murray: &#8220;Hate is Thriving in New Jersey&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://www.nj.com/opinion/2021/03/hate-is-thriving-in-new-jersey-opinion.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 13:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity and Inclusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monmouth In The News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspectives, Publications, and Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polling Institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>New Jersey easily ranks as one of the most racially and culturally diverse states in the country. In fact, nearly one in four residents were born outside the United States. This diversity brings a vitality to life in the Garden State that can be found in few other places. Unfortunately, it brings a lot of hate, as well.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nj.com/opinion/2021/03/hate-is-thriving-in-new-jersey-opinion.html">Murray: &#8220;Hate is Thriving in New Jersey&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nj.com/opinion/2021/03/hate-is-thriving-in-new-jersey-opinion.html">Murray: &#8220;Hate is Thriving in New Jersey&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2019/08/Murray-Patrick_square.jpg" length="45469" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Emerita Stafford and &#8220;The Long Campaign&#8221; for Women&#8217;s Studies at UNR</title>
		<link>https://www.unr.edu/nevada-today/news/2021/the-long-campaign#rebecca-stafford</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Maiden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 21:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Campus and Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity and Inclusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monmouth In The News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.monmouth.edu/news/?p=40802254261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Although Stafford’s appointment was historic – she was the institution’s first female appointed dean of a college other than the traditionally female colleges of Nursing and Home Economics – her selection also was a vivid example of the forces female faculty faced as they worked to gain traction on campus.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.unr.edu/nevada-today/news/2021/the-long-campaign#rebecca-stafford">President Emerita Stafford and &#8220;The Long Campaign&#8221; for Women&#8217;s Studies at UNR</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.unr.edu/nevada-today/news/2021/the-long-campaign#rebecca-stafford">President Emerita Stafford and &#8220;The Long Campaign&#8221; for Women&#8217;s Studies at UNR</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.monmouth.edu/news">News</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.monmouth.edu/news/wp-content/uploads/sites/16/2021/03/Rebecca-Stafford.jpg" length="88558" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
